const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which of the following can be found in the brain in neurosarcoidosis?","answers":[{"option":"Reactive gliosis","bool":false},{"option":"Liquefactive necrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Plaques in MRI","bool":false},{"option":"Gliotic scars","bool":false},{"option":"Non-caseating granulomas","bool":true}]},{"id":1,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"What is the antidote to benzodiazepine poisoning?","answers":[{"option":"Activated charcoal","bool":false},{"option":"N-acetylcysteine","bool":false},{"option":"Flumazenil","bool":true},{"option":"Deferoxamine","bool":false},{"option":"Physostigmine","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which of the following is not a risk factor for subdural hematoma?","answers":[{"option":"Chronic alcoholism","bool":false},{"option":"Old age","bool":false},{"option":"Head trauma","bool":false},{"option":"Smoking","bool":true},{"option":"Previous shunt surgery","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which of these is the first-line investigation in a patient presenting with subarachnoid hemorrhage?","answers":[{"option":"Contrast enhanced computed tomography","bool":false},{"option":"Lumbar puncture","bool":false},{"option":"Magnetic resonance imaging","bool":false},{"option":"Ultrasound","bool":false},{"option":"Plain computed tomography","bool":true}]},{"id":4,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which of the following disorder is not a risk factor for suicide?","answers":[{"option":"Alcohol abuse","bool":false},{"option":"Depressive disorder","bool":false},{"option":"Personality disorder","bool":false},{"option":"Obsessive-compulsive disorder (OCD)","bool":true},{"option":"Schizophrenic disorder","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"A 25-year-old male presents to the emergency room with sudden urinary retention and lower limb weakness. The neurosurgeon is called, urgent surgery is recommended after relevant imaging studies. To establish a diagnosis of cauda equina syndrome, besides the aforementioned symptoms, what other clinical feature must be present?","answers":[{"option":"Bilateral foot drop","bool":false},{"option":"Increased bulk below knee joints","bool":false},{"option":"Brisk reflexes in lower limbs","bool":false},{"option":"Saddle anesthesia","bool":true},{"option":"Increased muscle tone","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"A 65-year-old male presents to the clinic with progressive bilateral asymmetric tremors, which disappear upon performing routine activities. He has no history of forgetfulness. His attendants notice his movements are slow and sluggish. There is no history of falls, difficulty in swallowing, or respiratory problems. Upon questioning, his daughter reports a long history of constipation and sleep issues such as dream reenactments and insomnia. An MRI of the brain shows insignificant age-related changes. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Lewy body dementia","bool":false},{"option":"Huntington disease","bool":false},{"option":"Severe depression","bool":false},{"option":"Parkinson disease","bool":true},{"option":"Multiple cortical infarcts","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"According to the McDonald criteria for the diagnosis of multiple sclerosis, if a patient has 2 episodes separated in time and space, with clinical evidence of at least 2 lesions on MRI, what further investigations are required for the diagnosis of MS?","answers":[{"option":"No further requirement as clinical evidence alone suffices","bool":true},{"option":"Wait 1 year to assess disease progression","bool":false},{"option":"Wait for another lesion with additional attacks","bool":false},{"option":"Wait for seeing a rise in intracranial pressure to perform lumbar puncture","bool":false},{"option":"Wait for another episode as further imaging needed","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"What is the first-line drug used in the treatment of status epilepticus?","answers":[{"option":"Flumazenil","bool":false},{"option":"Phenytoin","bool":false},{"option":"Fosphenytoin","bool":false},{"option":"Diazepam","bool":true},{"option":"Parenteral valporic acid","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"What is the first-line treatment for trigeminal neuralgia?","answers":[{"option":"Phenytoin","bool":false},{"option":"Lamotrigine","bool":false},{"option":"Ethosuximide","bool":false},{"option":"Carbamazepine","bool":true},{"option":"Gabapentin","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"In which of the following ways does HIV encephalitis cause brain damage?","answers":[{"option":"Viral toxins and cytokines","bool":false},{"option":"CNS lymphoma","bool":false},{"option":"All of these","bool":true},{"option":"Gradual decline in cognitive function","bool":false},{"option":"Opportunistic infections","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which of these conditions is the greatest risk factor for suicide?","answers":[{"option":"Female gender","bool":false},{"option":"Puerperium","bool":false},{"option":"Depression","bool":true},{"option":"Obsessive-compulsive disorder","bool":false},{"option":"Parkinson's disease","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which of these can prevent complications in Streptococcus pneumoniae meningitis if given at an early stage?","answers":[{"option":"Corticosteroids","bool":true},{"option":"Antibiotics","bool":false},{"option":"Anti-epileptic drugs","bool":false},{"option":"Hormonal therapy","bool":false},{"option":"IV fluids","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which of these is a microglial marker?","answers":[{"option":"CD8","bool":false},{"option":"CD68","bool":true},{"option":"CD21","bool":false},{"option":"CD40","bool":false},{"option":"PTEN","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"What is another name for neurofilaments?","answers":[{"option":"Neurotransmitters","bool":false},{"option":"Neurotubules","bool":false},{"option":"Nodes of Ranvier","bool":false},{"option":"Nerve fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Neurofibrils","bool":true}]},{"id":15,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Coma involves which part of the brain?","answers":[{"option":"Pituitary gland","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Hippocampus","bool":false},{"option":"Hypothalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Diencephalon","bool":true}]},{"id":16,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"What is the appropriate management for meningocele?","answers":[{"option":"Laminectomy","bool":false},{"option":"No treatment","bool":false},{"option":"Repair within 48-72 hours","bool":true},{"option":"Laminotomy","bool":false},{"option":"Laminectomy with shunting","bool":false}]},{"id":17,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which of the following anxiety disorders comprises of specific conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Post-traumatic stress disorder","bool":false},{"option":"Panic disorder","bool":false},{"option":"Generalized anxiety disorder","bool":false},{"option":"Phobic anxiety disorder","bool":true},{"option":"Obsessive-compulsive disorder","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"What is the most common complication of bacterial meningitis?","answers":[{"option":"Epilepsy","bool":false},{"option":"Cognitive impairment","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrocephalus","bool":false},{"option":"Abscess","bool":false},{"option":"Hearing loss","bool":true}]},{"id":19,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"What type of speech is observed in patients with mania?","answers":[{"option":"Poverty of speech","bool":false},{"option":"Incoherent","bool":false},{"option":"Sing-song","bool":false},{"option":"Flight of ideas","bool":true},{"option":"Disorganized (word salad)","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which cranial nerve carries sensory information in the corneal reflex?","answers":[{"option":"Cranial nerve III","bool":false},{"option":"Cranial nerve VII","bool":false},{"option":"Cranial nerve XI","bool":false},{"option":"Cranial nerve V","bool":true},{"option":"Cranial nerve IV","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which of the following is the most common mechanism of action of antipsychotic drugs?","answers":[{"option":"Beta-adrenergic activity","bool":false},{"option":"Increase serotonin levels","bool":false},{"option":"Alpha-adrenergic activity","bool":false},{"option":"Decrease norepinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Decrease dopamine levels","bool":true}]},{"id":22,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"What is the most common peripheral neuropathy seen in diabetes mellitus?","answers":[{"option":"Optic neuritis","bool":false},{"option":"Sensory","bool":false},{"option":"Focal","bool":false},{"option":"Mononeuritis multiplex","bool":false},{"option":"Polyneuropathy","bool":true}]},{"id":23,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Why is epinephrine recommended in local anesthesia?","answers":[{"option":"It is easily reversible","bool":false},{"option":"It vasoconstricts and prolongs anesthesia","bool":true},{"option":"It is rapid acting","bool":false},{"option":"It is a vasodilator","bool":false},{"option":"It increases body secretions","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which of these is a cause of reversible dementia?","answers":[{"option":"Extracellular deposition of amyloid protein","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased dendritic branching","bool":false},{"option":"Intercellular neurofibrillary tangles","bool":false},{"option":"Cortical lewy bodies","bool":false},{"option":"Alcohol consumption","bool":true}]},{"id":25,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"What investigation is used to diagnose a child with cerebral palsy?","answers":[{"option":"X-ray Water's view","bool":false},{"option":"Magnetic resonance imaging","bool":true},{"option":"Cognitive function testing","bool":false},{"option":"Cranial ultrasonography","bool":false},{"option":"Head CT with contrast","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"A 37-year-old male presents to the neurology outpatient department with drooping eyelids and double vision. He is diagnosed with oculomotor nerve palsy. Damage to which vessel is most likely to cause his condition?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior inferior cerebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior cerebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior communicating artery","bool":true},{"option":"Middle cerebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior cerebral artery","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"What type of speech is observed in patients with Parkinson disease?","answers":[{"option":"Sing-song","bool":false},{"option":"Disorganized (word salad)","bool":false},{"option":"Difficult to interpret","bool":false},{"option":"Soft and rapid","bool":true},{"option":"Flight of ideas","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which of these is the cause of congenital cerebral palsy in a child?","answers":[{"option":"Premature birth","bool":true},{"option":"Maternal-fetal Rh incompatibility","bool":false},{"option":"Congenital infection","bool":false},{"option":"Genetic aberration","bool":false},{"option":"Trauma","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"What is the most common site for metastasis of a tumor?","answers":[{"option":"Lung","bool":true},{"option":"Intestines","bool":false},{"option":"Kidney","bool":false},{"option":"Colon","bool":false},{"option":"Breast","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"What is the most common and preventable cause of fetal and neonatal brain damage?","answers":[{"option":"Vitamin D deficinecy","bool":false},{"option":"Genetic abberation","bool":false},{"option":"Trauma","bool":false},{"option":"Folic acid deficiency","bool":true},{"option":"Accumulation of bilirubin","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"What is the most common histopathological finding in multiple sclerosis (MS)?","answers":[{"option":"Neurofibrillary tangles","bool":false},{"option":"Gliosis","bool":false},{"option":"Demyelinated plaques","bool":true},{"option":"Neurodegeneration","bool":false},{"option":"Lewy body accumulation","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which of the following is an indication for migraine prophylaxis?","answers":[{"option":"Satisfactory response to acute therapy","bool":false},{"option":"Severe unilateral orbital pain","bool":false},{"option":"One attack per month","bool":false},{"option":"Non-pulsating type of headache","bool":false},{"option":"Two or more attacks per month","bool":true}]},{"id":33,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which of these is given to pregnant women in order to prevent brain damage and psychomotor developmental issues in the fetus?","answers":[{"option":"Vitamin D","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin B12","bool":false},{"option":"Folic acid","bool":true},{"option":"Vitamin C","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Ketamine causes dissociative anesthesia. Which of these is not associated with dissociative anesthesia caused by ketamine?","answers":[{"option":"Sedation","bool":false},{"option":"Post-anesthesia confusion","bool":false},{"option":"Vivid dreams","bool":false},{"option":"Analog of phencyclidine (PCP)","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchoconstriction","bool":true}]},{"id":35,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Anosmia is caused by damage to which nerve?","answers":[{"option":"Cranial nerve III","bool":false},{"option":"Cranial nerve V","bool":false},{"option":"Cranial nerve II","bool":false},{"option":"Cranial nerve I","bool":true},{"option":"Cranial nerve IV","bool":false}]},{"id":36,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"What does a lesion in the right optic tract cause?","answers":[{"option":"Monoccular blindness","bool":false},{"option":"Right homonymous hemianopia","bool":false},{"option":"Complete blindness","bool":false},{"option":"Left homonymous hemianopia","bool":true},{"option":"Heteronymous hemianopia","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which modality affects T1 and T2?","answers":[{"option":"Repetition time (TR) and time to echo (TE)","bool":true},{"option":"Matrix size","bool":false},{"option":"Field of view","bool":false},{"option":"Number of excitations (NEX)","bool":false},{"option":"Slice thickness","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"What is the pathophysiology of depressive disorder?","answers":[{"option":"Loss of neurons","bool":false},{"option":"Alcohol consumption","bool":false},{"option":"Intercellular neurofibrillary tangles","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased serotonin","bool":true},{"option":"Lewy body dementia","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"Which of these is the most important risk factor for suicide worldwide?","answers":[{"option":"Drug addiction","bool":false},{"option":"Prior suicide attempt","bool":true},{"option":"Work-related stress","bool":false},{"option":"Relationship stress","bool":false},{"option":"Alcohol dependence","bool":false}]},{"id":40,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"What is the cause of pupil-sparing oculomotor nerve palsy?","answers":[{"option":"Lewy body dementia","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior communicating artery aneurysm","bool":false},{"option":"Diabetes mellitus","bool":true},{"option":"Depressive disorder","bool":false},{"option":"Genetic aberration","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"4th-year/neuroscience/2017","question":"A 6-month-old child is brought by his parents to the outpatient department and he presents with recurrent seizures, infantile spasms, and mental retardation. Upon performing an interictal electroencephalogram (EEG), a pattern of hypsarrhythmia is obtained. What is the likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Infantile neuroaxonal dystrophy (INAD)","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral palsy","bool":false},{"option":"Stroke","bool":false},{"option":"Encephalopathy","bool":false},{"option":"West syndrome","bool":true}]}]
export default arr